ALEXANDROS SOUMPLIS



Head of Systems Development

I like to consider myself an IT enthusiast and certainly a Linux expert. I have gone through the whole path of engineering, starting as a helpdesk operator for dial up Internet connections and now I am a cloud engineer with particular focus on OpenStack and Kubernetes. I like spending my spare time with family and do various nature-related activities, such as scuba diving, canyoning, sailing etc.

EXPERIENCE

HEAD OF SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT $fedsymbol{ abla}$ national infrastructures

FOR RESEARCH AND TECHNOLOGY (GRNET) since August 2018, Team lead of cloud engineering team that designed, built and operates the first OpenStack public cloud for the academic and research community in Greece. Currently runs with 220+ compute hosts, offering almost 10K CPU cores, 44TB RAM and 1,5PB storage. The project also required the full deployment of the operations ecosystem, including health and perfromance monitoring, log aggregation and analysis occurity audit and other. and analysis, security audit and other.

CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER ▼ STAVROS NIARCHOS FOUNDATION CULTURAL CENTER (SNFCC)

January 2016 - August 2018 , Executive role in charge of the technology delpoyment and operation in the SNFCC premises, hosting National Library of Greece and the Greek National Opera. We provided full infrastructure and IT services to both organizations and also visitor, exceeding 2M per year.

HEAD OF NOC / SENIOR SYSTEMS ENGINEER ▼ NATIONAL DOCUMENTATION CENTRE (EKT)

April 2007 - December 2015, Initially senior systems engineer and then Head of Network Operations Center and in charge of design, deploy and operations of the core ICT infrastructure, ICT services and digital data services. Main responsibilities including devops, virtualization, cloud storage, web services, high availability and scalability, monitoring and capacity planning

SYSTEMS ENGINEER (UNIX) $f \nabla$ **IDEAL SYSTEMS S.A.** May 2002 - February 2015,

TECHNICAL SUPPORT ∇ **FORTHNET S.A.** July 1999 - April 2002,

EDUCATION

MSC "PERVASIVE AND MOBILE COMPUTING SYSTEMS" Hellenic Open University

MSC "MANAGEMENT AND ADMINISTRATION OF BUSINESS AND ORGANISATIONS" National and Kapodistrian University of Athens

MSC "NFTWORKING AND DATA COMMUNICATIONS"